hey guys sh said welcome to concept and
coding and you already know that in
Spring boot I'm going to start Spring
Security and to understand it better
it's very much Essential to understand
the common attacks also then only we
would be able to understand the
importance of Spring Security okay so in
today's video I will cover very very
important topics with demo like how
these attacks happen and how we can
protect them like we can see that also
in in detail Spring Security how to
protect these attacks but today let's
understand what are this attacks how it
happen with a demo the first very
important and sometime it's asked in an
interview also csrf cross site request
forgery what does it do just see this
point first user is already
authenticated to a site okay let's say
that you have one
side something let's say Gmail
. you are already
authenticated okay the csrf attack
tricks a browser into making unwanted
request to a site where user is already
authenticated so what does it line says
that so this means that this attack what
it does is that your browser so now
let's say that for a minute this is a
session based you can say that
authentication your browser
okay your browser in your
cookie has a session stored has a
session ID is
stored now let's say that when you get
some
link click
here and this is link is hosted by some
attacker like it's not from a genuine
and you somehow attacker tricked you
that hey click you click here then your
will get resolved or something and now
you clicked here now what happen is with
the help of this csrf attack what this
attacker will do is it will make an
unwanted request to this site where you
already authenticated and it your
browser will automatically add the
session ID while sending this request
okay so it will also send this cookie
and this session ID browsers generally
automatically adds it
okay this
session so now when gmail.com request
will come let's say it's uh for
accessing some mail it will say that yes
cookie this session this session is
already valid and it will grant the
access so you are totally unaware of
this that hey only you click on this
link this click is intend to do
something else but in the background it
initiated one request on your behalf
using and your browser is is adding your
session so that's what it says that csrf
ATT tricks a browser into making
unwanted requests to a site where user
is already
authenticated mostly applicable where
State and session is managed so it's a
like a state
full right or session is managed only in
that so you know right there are two
types stateless and stateful so
generally this attack is mostly you can
say that happen with state is maintained
your cookie in this your state session
is maintained right so let me show you a
demo of this one just for demo purpose
I'm using a spring boot
only don't worry about this we will
discuss in depth when we will learn
spring board security but here you just
need to concentrate on
this your server let's say that you
whatever the server you are running
either Gmail or either anything Bank
anything you have specifically mentioned
that hey what no matter whatever the
request is you have to authenticate it
without authentication no request should
comes to me yes good right we have done
that and you have an end point like
where we have to do transfer money
transfer SL transfer and if this
request get initiated it will transfer
the
amount to whatever to whom you have
mentioned just a uh test testing
purpose so now what your expectation
from this is like anyone who is calling
this API is already authenticated
because I have put into that like any
request no matter any request should be
authenticated should be
authenticated okay so now let's see this
one is step
one we will also see this in parallel
what is the step one
I am making a user authenticated on a
server now let's see that now let's
first try to get ourself authenticated
on a particular server so in this case I
am running a server on my Local Host
just assume that it could be anything
Gmail Facebook Instagram where you are
authenticated and we are for now
assuming that it's a session based
authentication means in cookies some
session ID would be stored so let me
also open inspect element user
and let me put a password don't worry
about this how I got this password we
will cover this into Spring Security in
depth so now let's say I am
authenticated myself sign in so what has
happened is here if you see that when I
try to do a
login I got one session one session is
attached or return in the cookie and the
same session is getting maintained by
the server
also now
what is the Second
Step okay this see this on red in
cookies in the response one session got
added now let's say that some malous
link to this
user is received through email or um
through any other way or let's say just
browsing some websites and he said said
okay got this link so what would happen
so I have just created one basic
HTML where what happen is whenever you
click a link here internally it will
call this transfer API which we have
created right to transfer the amount
okay but here if you see that I am not
attaching any cookie or session that
your browser will automatically do okay
browser will add whenever any request is
sent browser adds the session okay so
this is the HTML now also let me open
the inspect element now just assume that
you got some link through WhatsApp
through Gmail or through while browsing
and somehow you click any malous link
see transfer $1,000 to
attacker and here if you
see in the request the session has been
added what is the session mm e1n it
should be the same as this one mme
e1n so your browser adds the session
whenever any request is made from like
from your browser okay so that is where
you can say that it's a csrf
attack where attacker tricks your
browser into making unwanted requests
where user is already authentic
indicated I hope that clarifies don't
worry about this uh how this
uh this one happening what I have
written we will see that into Spring
Security but for now you need to
understand what is this
attack okay we have seen that in the
attack wherever uh the browser
automatically adds the session which is
generally the same as what you got when
you were authenticated because browser
stores it in the cookie so how to get
protected from the csrf attack by using
csrf token so
generally apart from the
cookie if you want to get protected from
the csrf attack there is something
called csrf token
also okay so browser you can say that
server Returns the token in response
also and this token is you can say that
known only to an authenticated
legitimate source so as authenticate
forms or website only append the csrf
token in the
request okay so if I am making if I am
an attacker I using this HTML I don't
know what is the csrf token what value I
need to put I don't know only those who
are legitimate Source they know what is
the token and they will only append it
so that your server knows that okay this
request is coming from a legitimate
Source or
not the second attack is xss cross side
scripting very very important
okay understand it from a use case where
you have a web page where considered as
a
comments okay user one its comments user
to its comments now there is something
called post
you have to post something okay and once
you post it it will also be shown here
like I have posted let's say my commment
it will come so for
now what xss does is it allow a attacker
to put a malous script into a web page
viewed by other user so now let's say
that this is the web page if you come
you also see the comments from different
users and you can also post your
comments also so what if you inside a
post instead of writing you put a script
some and then a script would be stored
now any other user comes to this web
page it comments would be shown by user
one user two and also your comment where
you have put a script so that script
will
run
so commonly used for steing the session
or deform the website okay I will tell
you how we will see a demo
so for demo purpose I am creating two
endpoints one is a get Call of this/
exes where it will what it will do is it
will just load all the comments which
are present just return it nothing
else okay and also you will see that I
am using controller not rest controller
okay why because uh I want to render the
page I want to render the page I will
see you I will show you with an example
what does it mean the
second API is post SL commment what here
what it will do is this you are allowed
to post anything and that will stored it
in somewhere in the DB or somewhere in
memory and during get call that whole
complete list would be shown very simple
and this is a code I have written very
basic so I have used at theate
controller and if you have following the
spring boot playlist you know that what
is the difference between controller and
dress controller okay since I am using
controller I'm returning xss it will try
to load xs. HML it will try to render it
okay so there I have created one xs.
HTML okay so now here if you see this
get end point is like
just whenever this is called it will
just simply return all the comments all
the comments right whatever we have and
in the
post I am just adding a comment whatever
the comment I am coming see whatever the
comments I'm getting in a string
directly whatever the user is putting
some script or something I directly
added into my list okay since in the
spring boot everything is a single turn
only one object is created so that's
where even if you hit multiple times it
will get stored into this objects only
okay okay so don't get confused why why
not creating every time new object so
anytime you add a new comment it will
keep on appending to this list okay and
during get it will simply return all the
list okay so now let's see step one I am
hitting slash xss okay so here it will
render this
page here I am rendering this page leave
a comment and simply you are able to see
whatever the script you want to put or
comment you want to put you can see
submit okay and all the comments will be
shown
here so let's see okay so here if you
see that leave a
comment now let's see I am an attacker
and I have put script alert xss attack
some any just basic script now once I
call This And click on submit what would
happen see it's a attack happen there is
a popup comes
why because your browser initiated the
script
itself your browser initiated the script
itself
so when you click on
submit you first click the post API this
is the post end point so means this
comment got stored this comment got
stored now let's say any other any other
user is coming and to this web page so
definitely there is a get call happen SL
xss okay and it will load all the
comments and as soon as this scripted
comment get loaded your browser will
execute it and this uh popup comes now
you will say that hey what's the problem
in this so it's not uh uh like harmful
right it's just a popup just assume that
from this a simple script what if I
change to this
one I am taking you to some attacker
site
and just say that this is the attacker
link URI you don't even know and in the
request I just put document. cookie you
know that now whatever the cookie is
present in your browser will get to the
attacker now attacker knows your cookie
and this cookie only has your session ID
now wherever you are authenticated where
this session ID is applicable attacker
can access it freely
totally so it is not just like one popup
attack you can replace this inside in
instead of simple alert you can change
it to like this by for stealing your
cookie now attacker has your cookie your
session you will lose the data or the
security
compromise so what shall we do to
protect it so
generally we have to do proper escaping
the user input so wherever we are
accepting the user
input we don't know what user is
entering so we have to take this special
characters and we have to properly
Escape it like this has to be changed to
this okay so that browser don't treat it
as any script which it has to run so it
will be shown as it is like an string so
you don't have to worry about that your
any script will
run okay and you have to do proper
validation what what values are allowed
what values are not allowed in the like
user can
use so ex is clear
right there is something called C also
very important cross origin resource
sharing so first of all it's not an
attack but more of a security feature
which you can enable it or disable it
okay that it's a security feature that
restrict web pages from making request
to different origin unless Allowed by
the server so here if you see that first
of all what do you mean by different
origin different origin is like protocol
plus domain Plus Port so let's say that
for example this your client is sending
this so this is your
server okay and request can come from
anywhere some let's say that valid
clients and some attacker
also now server should tell that hey
only these are allowed if I get a
request from
these URLs then only allowed it
otherwise I will not entertain it okay
so that's where like protocol domain and
Port all three should be defined so that
server knows that yes only if there is a
matching request coming from this then
only I will entertain
for example client is like https some
local L 8080 and your server is running
on
HTTP again it is considered as a
different origin not the same origin if
it is the same origin it will uh no
issues it will like from the same uh
authenticated user valid client only but
the problem comes when the like
different origin like so consider this
as use as a different origin because
protocol is different client is running
on HTTP as server is running on HTTP
again it is considered
as different
origin so means here server has to allow
the request from
https local L
8080 similarly let's say port numbers
are different then also it is considered
a different origin similarly client is
running on sub. local server is running
on local then again it is considered as
different origin
so in all these scenarios server has to
specifically Whit list
this so that request can be entertained
from here and how you can do that by
setting exess control allw origin there
is whenever you hit a request you will
see this in this one we have to set so
here just don't worry about this we will
see into Spring Security but here if you
see that I am allowing this one
course configuration allowed origin list
what all is allowed I am putting here so
allowed https sub Local H 9090 I am
allowing only this URL for get postp put
delete purpose okay and this is the
allowed
header so I will allow any request
coming from this but not from this but
not from this so This Way
you can manage or you can say that it's
a security feature like you can say that
consider this request like the first
csrf attack okay so you can say that
course can become the first security
gate maybe you csrf token is required
that is must okay but you can say that
this course can become a first line of
defense that if you are uh clicking on
some of the link and that server the
attacker server is running on some other
uh different
origin this is C become the first line
of defense
that it will not even
entertain okay because server has only
allowed request from this
itself and the last one is SQL injection
in this one attacker manipulates SQL
query
by inserting malous input into the user
field so I'm creating a very very simple
here let's say that search
field now whatever you put search let's
say that uh cold
drinks what if you are using this input
and putting into query select estess
from products
where uh type equals to and this
whatever it is coming
search value you are directly using
whatever user is putting into your DB
query so here I can put some
malous uh you can say that query which
can even like give me
the data which for which I'm not even
authenticated or even I can delete your
DB also or get your DB table name
complete right so with SQL injection
like your DB is not safe even I can get
what is the table what are the column
name I can delete it or I can access the
unauthorized data also from the DB so in
this example I'm showing this only very
simple find API and I'm using this
whatever the name is given by the user
I'm directly putting into the query okay
so now here if you see in
my DB currently there are two
users okay and my query says that
whatever the username comes only that
would be return if a a a comes only that
should be
written but now let's say that what if I
put hit the query like this SL
find here if you see Slash find now
instead of name I am giving like this
slash
or 1 = to 1 now directly it will replace
here so what it will be like user undor
name equals to so first this will finish
this then it will append this or 1 = to
1 and then you have this one which will
complete this now your query become this
select estess from user details where
username equals to this so it is empty
or 1al to 1 become true so it will
return all the values in the
DB you you got it like what happened
here I put certain values which is
not properly uh you can say that
validated and used directly into the
query and I manipulated it such that it
returns me the complete data or
unauthorized
data we can also use it to F the DB name
table name and you can also drop the D
DB also tables also so it's very very
important uh to get protected from the
SQL injection and how to protect it by
we have already seen that in the SQL
when we covered jpql right by
parameterized query we can protect it so
whatever the name is coming don't use it
as it is you have to use like this
parameterize
it okay so set parameters so that it
would be like not as considered as a
query it will be considered as a value
string okay and then you will get no
data so because with this name/ all 1al
to 1 nothing matched
so it's safe
now okay guys any doubt let me know uh
we'll discuss more thank you bye